# A1. (As listed under "Project requirements")

I chose to utilize the professional website- I've already completed the portfolio needed for the SISLT program. While I have an education undergraduate degree, I am not a teacher.

Since I am not currently seeking a job (I have a full time library position at a nursing school), I went with the concept of a promotional site for an independent business side project I thought about one time; providing a "home library" service.

(A2, as listed in the description of the "professional site")

#### Welcome!

Are you looking for a professional librarian to help organize your home collections of books, movies, or music? Then you're in the right place! My name is Sarah, and let me show you why I'm the person to call for your media organizing needs.

#### **About Me:**

Some people meditate. Some people have a glass of wine. I find my zen in a pile of books or a list of titles. I find happiness in a straightened shelf or organized ebook files. I have been working in libraries since I was sixteen and enjoy learning about a number of different subjects. I have worked with children, teens, adults, students, and faculty, providing reader's advisory and organized material for them. Formats I've worked in include Dewey Decimal System, Library of Congress, and National Library of Medicine. I've curated attractive collections and displays, so not only will your collection be organized in a way that you can understand, it will look good with your home decor. I'm skilled in the use of programs like Excel, Calibre, and Book Crawler for cataloging usage. My hobbies include Dungeons and Dragons, reading (usually fantasy, sci-fi, or graphic novels), and video games.

### **Degrees and Certifications:**

Masters of Library and Information Science B.S. in Secondary Education with Certification in English

### **Experience:**

I have worked as a Teen and Youth Services Specialist and have worked in both academic and specialized libraries.

St. Peter's Nursing College Lyon University Deacon Public Library

### **Skills:**

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Publisher
Internet (effective browsing and navigation), email, and social networking programs
Databases: CINAHL, MEDLINE, Pubmed, NoveList, Learning Express Library, etc.
Virtual meeting software and programs such as FaceTime, GotoMeeting, and Skype
Video game consoles and digital distribution platforms such as Steam

#### **Favorite Quotes:**

"When you do things right, people won't be sure you've done anything at all" --God Entity, Futurama

"For me, I am driven by two main philosophies, know more today about the world than I knew yesterday. And along the way, lessen the suffering of others. You'd be surprised how far that gets you" --Neil deGrasse Tyson

## **Experience**

My experience includes work with the public, students, and researchers. Through these positions, I have become familiar with the resources needed for a diverse group of individuals. Whether it's finding a board book for a baby or a Cochrane Review for a researcher, I have learned about a wide range of subjects and know the best way to make them accessible. I keep up with trends in children and teen literature, and even if I might not know the more minute details of complex subjects such as medicine, I always know where to look in order to retrieve the information needed.

St. Peter's Nursing College
Library Assistant 2012 – Present
Assisting students with databases and research
Collection management
Working with vendors, participating in conferences and webinars dealing with issues related to library and medical library science

Lyon University
Library Assistant 2016 – 2018
Assisting students with databases, research, and APA formatting
Collection management

Deacon Library, Ellisville Branch
Youth Services II 2008 – 2010
Planning and executing programming for children and teens
Assisting patrons with reader's advisory and answering reference questions
Keeping up with current trends in children's and teen literature
Working with schools and community centers as part of the library's outreach programs

# My Current Resume:



(Link will be here)

## POWTOON VID CODE

<iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.powtoon.com/embed/dl61bpuDTiT/"
frameborder="0"></iframe>

Being a librarian/information specialist is more than straightening dusty books on a shelf. It's about providing people free and easy access to information, both factual and enriching. That could mean an online journal article, a DVD, access to a specialist in the field, a puzzle, a streaming documentary, and yes, even a book or two. A library is a safe and comfortable place where people learn and discover, and there are libraries for everybody, whether they are a member of a community, a student nurse, or a researcher. It's my job to make sure they have free and easy access to this information. The less time you spend searching for something, the more time you have to enjoy it.

George Carlin once said, "A house is just a place to keep your stuff while you go out and get more stuff". It certainly feels that way when you have collections, whether they are books, records, games or rocks. Like a library, your home is a safe and comfortable place where you can learn and discover what is most important to you. Your collections say a lot about you- your interests, experience, and values. A home library should be just that; a library in your home. Libraries are places for expressions of freedom, and when the things that you are passionate about aren't easy to get to or find, it can feel like you're missing a part of yourself.

Librarians love to help others discover and learn, and our beliefs are akin to those of educators. There's nothing more enjoyable than seeing someone learn, whether it's a first time experience, an "I had no idea this even existed", or just having a simple question answered. I love creating spaces where people can learn or just escape with a good book.

(as listed under "professional portfolio")

For questions or comments, please fill in the following information:

Name	
Email	
Question/comments	

I can also be reached at: Sum241z@aol.com 424-766-9336 (as listed under "project requirements")

# W

Web development issues	
0	Users and usability
0	Cross-browser compatibility
0	User accessibility
0	Search engine optimization
0	Responsive web design
Design	
0	Define the audience/set goals
0	Develop the site map
0	Wireframe the critical pages
0	Illustrate the critical pages